

JOSEPH DIAS

PROFILE

Expert Software Developer with 7+ years of experience in contributing in design and creation of scalable software to write clean and functional code on front-end and back-end. Minimize system downtime and quickly respond to changing needs of the business. Seasoned full stack developer with experience in training front-end and back-end developers and providing active feedback and hiring.

CONTACT

PHONE: +91 9420776309

Email josephdias92@gmail.com

Github Links: josephdias92 (Joseph Dias) · GitHub

Profile Links: Joseph Dias

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

J2SE/J2EE, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS, SOL

LIBRARIES & FRAMEWORKS

Spring boot, Angular, React, Vue, Node.js, Express

TOOLS & PLATFORMS

IntelliJ, Git, Webpack, Heroku, Firebase, VS code, Jenkins

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK ENGINEER CREDIT SUISSE, PUNE

Oct 2019 - Present

Successful contribution in migrating 5 applications from JAP to Angular and Spring boot using Agile Methodology. Performing as IT Owner for Asset Servicing Portal and Seclib applications. Guided, coached the new joiners from Pune and Zurich on various technologies related to Asset Servicing applications. Successfully implemented CI/CD for Asset Servicing Portal.

Proposed micro frontend architecture and implementation is in progress. Built reusable libraries (SECLIB) which are published to InnerSource for wider groups within Credit Suisse India.

Delivered high quality software for the SRD II program to support our business to meet the key regulatory requirements.

Provided swift resolutions to business towards production stability.

Major contributions towards hiring for Operations Technology India: Conducted interviews, hiring.

LEAD PROJECT ENGINEER PERSISTENT SYSTEM LIMITED, GOA

July 2017 - Oct 2019

Promoted to Lead Project Engineer from Sr. Front End Developer.

Responsible for end-to-end project delivery. Worked for AppDynamics in migrating the application from Adobe flash to Angular and Spring Boot technology.

Handled clients like IBM in Research projects for three different applications including building the application architecture.

JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER SRIJAN TECHNOLOGIES, GOA

Feb 2016 - June 2017

Worked with International clients to understand business needs and develop software solutions with necessary validations. Developed software to analyze and process data and statistics which works both online and offline.

Drive community technology consciousness/awareness by code sprints, sessions, demos, blogs, presentations.

Took complete ownership for the code quality, including review, guide and support other developers when required.

Actively participated in tech discussions, estimations, and supported Tech Leads in technical/architectural decisions.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER GARUD TECHNOLOGIES, GOA

July 2015 - Jan 2016

Created Angular project architecture. Created WebAPI in C# MVC. Deployed Angular application. Worked with Ionic framework (hybrid Application)

INTERNSHIP OPEN DESTINATION PRIVATE LIMITED

Jan 2015 - June 2015

EDUCATION

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION GOA UNIVERSITY

May 2012 - June 2015

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION ROSARY COLLEGE, NAVELIM, GOA

July 2009 - April 2012